Hugo:
Hi Chantal.
What did you think of the talk, then?
Chantal:
Hi Hugo.
I thought it was good once I’d moved seats.
Hugo:
Oh – were the people beside you chatting or something?
Chantal:
It wasn’t that.
I went early so that I’d get a seat
and not have to stand,
but then this guy sat right in front of me and he was
so tall!
Hugo:
It’s hard to see through people’s heads, isn’t it?
Chantal:
Impossible!
Anyway, to answer your question, I thought it was really interesting, especially what the
speaker said about the job market.
Hugo:
Me too.
I mean we know we’re going into a really competitive field
so it’s obvious that we may struggle to get work.
Chantal:
That’s right – and we know we can’t all have that ‘dream job’.
Hugo:
Yeah,
but it looks like there’s a whole range of … areas of work that
we hadn’t even thought of – like fashion journalism, for instance.
Chantal:
Yeah – I wasn’t expecting so many career options.
Hugo:
Mmm.
Overall, she had quite a strong message, didn’t she?
Chantal:
She did.
She kept saying things like ‘I know you all think this,
but …’ and then she’d tell us how it really is.
Hugo:
Perhaps she thinks students are a bit narrow-minded about the industry.
Chantal:
It was a bit harsh, though!
We know it’s a tough industry.
Hugo:
Yeah – and we’re only first years, after all.
We’ve got a lot to learn.
Chantal:
Exactly.
Do you think our secondary-school education should have been more career-focused?
Hugo:
Well, we had numerous talks on careers,
which was good,
but none of them were very inspiring.
They could have asked more people like today’s speaker to talk to us.
Chantal:
I agree.
We were told about lots of different careers – just when we needed to be,
but not by the experts who really know stuff.
Hugo:
So did today’s talk influence your thoughts on what career you’d like to take
up in the future?
Chantal:
Well, I promised myself that I’d go through this course
and keep an open mind till the end.
Hugo:
But I think it’s better to pick an area of the industry now
and then aim to get better and better at it.
Chantal:
Well, I think we’ll just have to differ on that issue!
Hugo:
One thing’s for certain, though.
From what she said, we’ll be unpaid assistants in the industry for quite a
long time.
Chantal:
Mmm.
Hugo:
I’m prepared for that, aren’t you?
Chantal:
Actually, I’m not going to accept that view.
Hugo:
Really?
But she knows it’s the case – and everyone else says the same.
Chantal:
That doesn’t mean it has to be true for me.
Hugo:
OK.
Well – I hope you’re right!
Chantal:
I thought the speaker’s account of her first job was fascinating.
Hugo:
Yeah – she admitted she was lucky to get work being a personal dresser
for a musician.
She didn’t even apply for the job and there she was getting paid to
choose all his clothes.
Chantal:
It must have felt amazing – though she said all she was looking for
back then was experience, not financial reward.
Hugo:
Mmm.
And then he was so mean, telling her she was more interested in her
own appearance than his!
Chantal:
But – she did realise he was right about that,
which really made me think.
I’m always considering my own clothes but now I can see you should be
focusing on your client!
Hugo:
She obviously regretted losing the job.
Chantal:
Well, as she said, she should have hidden her negative feelings about him,
but she didn’t.
Hugo:
It was really brave the way she picked herself up
and took that job in retail.
Fancy working in a shop after that!
Chantal:
Yeah – well, she recommended we all do it at some point.
I guess as a designer you’d get to find out some useful information, like how big
or small the average shopper is.
Hugo:
I think that’s an issue for manufacturers, not designers.
However, it would be useful to know if there’s a gap in the market
– you know, an item that no one’s stocking but that consumers are looking
for.
Chantal:
Yeah, people don’t give up searching.
They also take things back to the store if they aren’t right.
Hugo:
Yeah.
Imagine you worked in an expensive shop and you found out the garments sold there were being returned
because they … fell apart in the wash!
Chantal:
Yeah, it would be good to know that kind of thing.